O. H. Robertson Papers 1918-1966 Mss.B.R546
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Published works by others, 1.5 linear feet
  - Collins, Gerald B., Factors influencing the orientation of migrating anadromous fishes
  - Curry, John J., Clinical implications of the effect of various anticholinergic agents in modifying the pulmonary response of asthmatic subjects to injected methacholine
  - De Gowin, Elmer L., A plan for collection, transportation and administration of whole blood and of plasma in warfare
  - Dood, J. M., The hormones of the pituitary gland of the dog-fish.
  - Drinker, Philip, The Drinker respirator
  - Dunklin, Edward W., The lethal effect of relative humidity on air-borne bacteria
  - Edelman, Isidore S., Effects of corticosteroids on electrolyte metabolism during osmoregulation in teleosts
  - Etoh, Hisami, Effect of hypophysectomy and adrenalectomy on the length of survival time after X-irradiation in the gold fish
  - Felin, Frances E., Population heterogeneity in the Pacific Pilchard
  - Fontaine, Maurice, Corpuscules de Stanni us et régulation ionique du milieu intérieur de l'Anguille
  - Fontaine, M., Interrenal antérieur et smoltification chez Salmo salar L
  - Fontaine, Maurice, Evolution of form and function of endogrine organs with special reference to the adrenal gland.
  - Fourman, Julia, The effect of intra-arterial cushions on plasma skimming in small arteries
  - Freeman, Joseph T., The mechanisms of stress and the forces of senesce
  - Gjullin, C. M., The effect of some insecticides on black fly larva in Alaskan streams
  - Graeser, James B., Rationale of specific therapy in lobar pneumonia
  - Graeser, James B., Specific soluble substance of pneumococcus in lungs of dogs recovered from experimental lobar pneumonia
  - Graeser, James B., Changes in the titer of antipneumococcal humoral immunity in adult human beings
  - Grant, William C., Jr., Presence of the red EFT water-drive factor prolact in the pituitaries of teleosts
  - Gregg, Lucien A., Sulfapyridine in experimental pneumococcic pneumonia in the dog
  - Griffin, Philip J., A unique bacterium pathogenic for warm-blooded and cold-blooded animals
  - Hamburger, Morton, Jr., Ability of different typers of hemolytic streptococci to produce scarlet fever
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., The problem of the dangerous carrier of hemolytic streptococci. I. Number of hemolutic streptococci expelled by carriers with postive and negative nos cultures
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., II. Spread of infection by individuals with strongly positive nose cultures who expelled large numbers of hemolytic streptococci
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., III. The chemotherapeutic control of nasal carri
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., IV. Observations upon the role of the hands, of blowing the nose, of sneezing, and of coughing in the dispersal of these microorganisms
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., The significance of nose to throat carrier ratios in the epidemiology of hemolytic streptococcal infection
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., Studies on the transmission of hemolytic stroptococcus infections. I. Cross infections in army hospital wards
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., II. Beta hemolytic streptococci in the saliva of persons with positive throat cultures
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., Studies on the transmission of hemolytic streptococcus infections. III. Hemolytic streptococci in the air, floor dust, and bed-clothing of hospital wards and their relation to cross infection.
  - Hamburger, Morton Jr., Susceptibility to sulfadiazine of hemolytic streptococci recovered in army camps
  - Handin, Robert I., Effect of hypophysectomy on survival and on thyroid and interrenal histology of the cichlid teleost
  - Hargett, M. V., Aqueous=base yellow fever vaccine
  - Hasler, Arthur D., Odour perception and orientation in fishes
  - Hayes, Frederick Roland, The growth, general chemistry, and temperature relations of salmonid eggs
  - Hertz, Roy, Interference with hormonal effects by antivitamins and competition between structurally similar steroid hormones
  - Hickman, Cleveland P., Jr., The osmoregulatory role of the thyroid gland in the starry flounder
  - Hilles, Carolyn H., Experience with the slide agglutination and the capillary precipitin methods for typing hemolytic streptococci
  - Holmes, W., The peri-renal tissue of Protopterus. A contribut to the history of the adrenal
  - Honma, Yoshiharu, Another catadromous eel from the sea of Japan
  - Honma, Yoshiharu, A list of the fishes found in the vicinity of Sado Marine Biological Station. II.
  - Honma, Yoshiharu, On the Throid gland of two species of Seriola
  - Honma, Yoshiharu, On the thyroid gland of the Tuna
  - Huggins, Charles, Endocrine factors in cancer
  - Huggins, Charles,Mammary cancer induced by a single feeding of polynuclear hydrocarbons, and its suppression
  - Huggins, Charles, Propositions in hormonal treatment of advanced cancers
  - Idler, D. R., Olfactory perception in migrating salmon. I. L-serine, a salmon repellent in mammalian skin
  - Ingle, Dwight J., The biologic proberties of cortisone: a review
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Comparison of biologic effects of ACTH protein an ACTH peptide given by continuous injecton
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Comparison of some metabolic and morphologic effects of cortisone and hydrocortisone given by continuous injection to rats
  - Ingle, Dwight J., A consideration of the relationship of experimentally produced and naturally occurring pathologic changes in the rat to the adaptation diseases
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Effect of adrenal cortical extract, cortisone and hydrocortisone upon the work of the adrenalectomizes-eviscerate rat
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Effects of administering adrenocorticotrophic hormone by continueous injection to normal rats.
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Effect of Antibiotics upon survival of the eviscerate rat
  - Ingle, Dwight J., An effect of commercial preparations of corticotropin upon the work performance of the adrenalectomized-hypophysectomized rat
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Effects of administering cortisone acetate and diethylstilbestrol to normal force-fed rats
  - Ingle, Dwight J., Effects of administering large doses of cortisone acetate to normal rats
  - Ingle, Dwight J., The effect of some partially purified preparations of corticotrophin upon the work performance of adrenalectomized-hypophysectomized rats
  - Ingle, Dwight J., The effect of some stressors on symptoms of cortisone overdosage
  - Ingle, Dwight J., An extra-adrenal effect of some commercial preparations of corticotropin upon the work performance of the hypophysectomized rat
  - Johnson, E. P., Triethylene glycol in the control of air-borne dissemination of pneumoencephalitis
  - Johnson, E. P., The use of glycol vapors in preventing spreading of Newcastle virus
  - Kahn, Reuben L., Effect of irradiation on the universal reaction in cancer
  - Kahn, Reuben L., Tissue immunity and aging
  - Kahn, Reuben L., X-irradiation and toxin neutralization by antitoxi
  - Kaye, Saul, Determination of small amounts of triethylene glycol in air
  - Kaye, Saul The use of ethylene oxide for the sterilization of hospital equipment
  - Kent, John F., Effect of corticotropin and cortisone on globule leucocytes of rat
  - Kerr, James E., Studies on fish preservation at the Contra Costa Steam plant of the Pacific gas and electric Co.
  - Klüver, Heinrich, Brain mechanisms and behavior with special reference to Rhinencephalon
  - Korenchevsky, V., Autointoxications and processes of ageing
  - Korenchevsky, V., Effects of castration and the processes of aging in male rats and man
  - Korenchevsky, V., Endocrines and aging
  - Korenchevsky, V., HyB4perplasias, metaplasias and adenomas in senescent male rats intact or treated with hormones
  - Korenchevsky, V., Problem of autointoxication in gerontology
  - Korenchevsky, V., Treatment of senescence in male rats with sex and thyroid hormones and desoxycorticosterone aceta
  - Krugman, Saul, Air sterilization in infants' ward
  - Lansing, Albert I., Atherosclerosis and the nature of the arterial walls
  - Lansing, Albert I., Increase of cortical calcium with age in the cells of Elodea Camadensis
  - Larkey, Sanford V., The national research council and medical preparedness
  - Leloup-Hatey, Jeanine Le cholestérol de LC-nterrénal antérieur de quelques poiss,ons téléostéens
  - Leloup-Hatey, Jeanine, Modifications de léquilibre minéral de l'Anguille conséeutives à láblation des corpuscules de Stannius
  - Leloup-Hatey, Jeanine, Etude du déterminisme de l'interrénal antériour observée chez quelques téléostéens...
  - Leloup-Hatey, Jeanine, Influence d'un apport sodique et de l'aldostérone sur le déséquilibre minéral consécutif à l'ablatior des corpuscules de Stannius chez l'Anguille
  - Leloup, Jacques, Fixation du radioiode dans la thyroi'de de deux Téléostéens marins: le congre et le muge
  - Leloup, Jacques, Influence de l'ablation de corpuscules de Stannius sur le fonctionnement thyroidien de l'Anguille normale et hypophysectomisée
  - Lemon, Henry M., Arrest of hormone-dependent cancer by pituitaryadrenal inhibition
  - Lemon, Henry M., Arrest of metastatic mammary carcinoma by cortisone and thyroid therapy
  - Lemon, Henry M., Bacterial content of air in army barracks
  - Lemon, Henry M A Flowmeter for use in air sampling procedures
  - Lemon, Henry M., A Method for collection of bacteria from air and textiles
  - Lemon, Henry M., Missed cases and contact carriers among nasal carriers of beta hemolytic streptococci
  - Lennon, Robert E., Feeding Mechanism of the sea lamprey and its effect on host fishes
  - Lerner, Aaron Bunden, MSH The melanocyte stimulating hormone
  - Lester, William Jr., The influence of relative humidity on the infectivity of air-borne influenza a virus (PR8 strain)
  - Lindsay, Stuart, Coronary arteriosclerosis of birds
  - Loosli, Clayton G., Pathogenesis and pathology of lobar pneumonia
  - Loosli, Clayton G., The transmission and control of respiratory diseases in army barracks. II. The spread of hemolytic streptococcal infections among enlisted personnel
  - Loosli, Clayton G., III, The suppression of dust-borne bacteria by oiling floors and bedclothes
  - Loosli, Clayton G.,An apparatus for nebulizing liquids
  - Loosli, Clayton G., Dust and its control as a means of disinfection of air
  - Loosli, Clayton G., Interalveolar communications in normal and in pathologic mammalian lungs
  - Luetscher, John, Aldosterone: observations on the regulation of sodium and potassium balance
  - March, Harold W., Persistence of a functioning bulbus cordis homologue in the turtle heart
  - Meisner, Herman M., Effect of temperature and photoperiod on the serum proteins of the rainbow trout
  - Miller, C. Phillip, Bacterial resistance to antibiotics
  - Moore, Carl R., Adrenal cortical secretions in relation to the reproductive system of rats
  - Moore, Frederick J., Pheumococcic pneumonia
  - Mooreshouse, D. E., Experimental alteration of the peri-renal tissue of Protopterus
  - Mosca, L., An experimental study of the cytology of pancreati islets
  - Moulton, Stanley, An apparatus for determination of the bacterial content of air
  - Muether, R. O., Studies on "stored blood" I. Technic for storage blood
  - Muether, R O II. Effect of storage on human blood
  - Muether, R. O., Effects of stored blood on the recipient
  - Muether, R. O., Studies and uses of stored blood and plasma
  - Nandi, Jean, Corticosteroid production by interrenal tissue of teleost fishes
  - Needham, Paul R., Book Review. Freshwater Fishery Biology by Karl F. Lagler
  - Needham, Paul R., Rainbow trout in Mexico and California
  - Nigrelli, Ross V., Spontaneous neoplasms in fishes. VI. Thyroid tumors in marine fishes
  - Noall, Matthew W., Endocrine control of amino acid transfer
  - Nutini, Leo G., The universal serologic reaction in Brown-Pearce carcinoma
  - O'Connell, Charles P., The life history of the Cabezon
  - Ogawa, Mizuho, On the corpuscles of stannius of goldfish treated with sea water
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Action de divers antithyroidiens sur la destinée de l'iode radioactif I dans la glande thyroide d'un pelacien
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Action de divers antithyroidiens sur la structure histologique de la thyroide de quelques teleostéens marins
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Action de la thiourée et du thiouracile sur le comportement de l'iode radioactif dans la glande thyroide de deux Téléostéens marins
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Effect de la radiothyroidectomie sur l'interrénal de l'Anguille
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Corpuscules de Stannius et reproduction chez l'Anguille mC"le.
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Cytologie adénohypophysaire chez les Agnathes, les Poissons et les Amphibiens
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Cytologie hypophysaire et antigéne sérique en relation avex la maturation sexualle chez Oncorhynchus species
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Fonction corticotrope et cytologie hypophysaire chez deux Téléostéens: Mollienesia latipinna le Sueur et Anguilla anguilla L
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Influence de la température sur l'historlogie thyroidienne de divers teleosteens
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Etude volumétrique de l'interrénal antérieur au cours de la smoltification de Salmon Salar L
  - Olivereau, Madeleine, Influence de l'hypophysectomie sur l'histologie de l'interrénal antérieur de l'anguille
  - Overbeeke, A. P. van, Histological studies on the interrenal and the phaeochromic tissue in teleostei
  - Panikkar, N. K., Some aspects of adaptation in Chanos Chanos
  - Park, Thomas, Competition: an experimental and statistical study
  - Park, Thomas, Experimental studies of interspecies competition II. Temperature, humidity, and competition in two species of tribolium
  - Parker, Robert R., Muscular fatigue and mortality in Troll-caught Chinook salmon
  - Perkins, James E., The present status of the control of air-borne infections
  - Pickford, Grace E., Endocrinological studies on the Euryhaline Killifis
  - Pickford, Grace E., Prolactin, a factor in promoting survivalof hypophysectomized Killifish in fresh water
  - Phillips, J. G., Corticosteroid productionin vitro by the interrena tissue of Killifish
  - Phillips, J. G., The identity of adrenocortical secretions in lower vertebrates
  - Polderman, L. D., Triethylene glycol for air samitation
  - Pressman, David, The zone of localization of anti-mouse-kidney Prigal, Samuel J serum as determined by radioautographs
  - Prigal, Samuel J., A new method of aerosolization of penicillin, sulfonamides, and other medications for inhalation therapy
  - Puck, Theodore, An automatic dewpoint meter for the determination of condensable vapors
  - Puck, Theodore, The dispersal and control of triethylene glycol vapor for aerial disinfection
  - Puck, Theodore, The mechanism of aerial disinfection by glycols and other chemical agents. I. & II.
  - Puck, Theodore, Studies in vapor-liquid equilibria. I A new dynamic method for the determination of vapor pressures of liquids
  - Redfern, William W., Skin reactions produced by antihuman serum
  - Rentschler, Harvey, Bactericidal action of ultraviolet readiation on air-borne organisms
  - Robertson, E Chant Air contamination and air sterilization
  - deRoos, Carolyn C., The corticoids of the adrenal of the California sea lion
  - Rounsefell, George A., Anadromy in North American Salmonidae
  - Rous, Peyton, Are carcinogens responsible for the superimposed neoplastic changes occurring in mouse tumor cells?
  - Rous, Peyton, Fatal keratomas due to deep homagrafts of the benign papillomas of tarred mouse skin
  - Rous, Peyton, The preservation of living red blood cells in vitro I. Methods of Preservation II. The transfusion of kept cells., 2 copies
  - Rous, Peyton, Surmise and fact on the natrue of cancer
  - Rous, Peyton, Viruses and tumour causation
  - Rous, Peyton, What cancer research has done
  - Rubinstein, L. J., Ageing changes in skeletal muscle
  - Schneider, Hans, Laute und lauterzeugung Beim süsswassertrommler aplodinotus grunniens rafinesque
  - Schjeide, Ole A., Proteins and calcium in serums of estrogen-treated roosters
  - Scudder, John, Newer knowledge of blood transfusions
  - Shapovalov, Leo, A check list of the fresh-water and anadromous fishes of California
  - Shock, N. W., Some physiological aspects of aging in man
  - Sindermann, Carl J., Blood properties of prespawning and postspawning anadromous alewives
  - Solez, Chester, Aging and adrenal cortical hormones
  - Sonkin, Lawrence S., Application of the cascade impactor to studies of bacterial aerosols
  - Sonkin, Lawrence S., Infections induced in mice by local application of streptococci and pneumococci to the nasal mucosa and by intrapulmonary instillation
  - Sonkin, Lawrence S., A modified cascade impactor
  - Strumia, Max M., The preparation and preservation of human plasma I. Collection of blood and separation of plasma
  - Strumia, Max M., Drawing off, pooling and distribution of plas
  - Sulya, L. L., Distribution of some blood constituents in fishes from the Gulf of Mexico
  - Sulya, L. L., Plasma proteins in the blood of fishes from the Gulf of Mexico
  - Sutliff, W. D., Adequate tests of curative therapy in man
  - Tampi, P. R. S., On the structure of the pituitary and thyroid of Chanos Chanos
  - Thomas, Caroline Bedell, Observations on some possible precursors of essen hypertension and coronary artery disease
  - Terrell, Edward E., Changes in humoral immunity occurring during the early stages of experimental pneumococcus infecti
  - United States Army Board for the investigation and control of influenza and other epidemic diseases in the army
  - Vastesaeger, Marcel M., L'Atherosclerose spontanée du thon rouge
  - Vastesaeger, Marcel M., The natural history of atherosclerosis
  - Vernon, Sidney, Connective tissue, hormones and aging
  - Viswanathan, R., Oxygen consumption and viability of Chanos Chanos in relation to size
  - Waring, James J., The anatomy of angling
  - Weisel, George F., The osteocranium of the catostomid fish. A study in adaptation and natural relationship
  - Weiss, Jules, Age changes in the fine structure of anterior pituitary of the mouse
  - Wells, William Firth, Radiant disinfection of air
  - Wells, William Firth, Sanitary ventilation
  - Wells, William Firth, Ventilation and atmospheric pollution
  - Welt, Isaac D., Effect of cortisone upon rates of glucose production and oxidation in the rat
  - Wilens, Sigmund L., The relationship between cortical hyperplasia of the adrenals and arteriosclerosis
  - Wilkinson, Allan B., Cushing's syndrome
  - Wise, Henry, Dispersal of triethylene glycol vapor with aeroso bombs
  - Wise, Henry, Saturation concentrations of triethylene glycol vapor at various relative humidities and temperat ures
  - Wohlschlag, Donald E., Antarctic fish growth and metabolic differences related to sex
  - Wohlschaag, Donald E., Metabolic requirements for thw swimming activity of three antarctic fishes
  - Woodhull, Chester A., The fish population of Salt Springs Valley Reserv Calaveras County, California
  - Wohlschaag, Donald E., Metabolic requirements for thw swimming activity of three antarctic fishes
  - Wright, A., Chromaffin tissue in the lizard adrenal gland World Health Organization Technical report series No.143 Classification of atherosclerotic lesions
  - Wu, Ching, Visceral displacement in pneumonia
- Series V. Bibliographic Index Files, 1.25 linear feet
  Bound slip-files of bibliographic references in ecology and medicine, organized bny author, with separate subject indexes. The latest entries are in the early 1960s.
  - Ecology, 4 vols.
    - Author Index (Box 11)
      - A-G (Box 11)
      - H-P (Box 11)
      - Q-Z (Box 11)
    - Subject Index
  - General, 5 vols.
    - Author Index (Box 12)
      - A-D (Box 12)
      - E-K (Box 12)
      - L-R (Box 12)
      - S-Z (Box 12)
    - Subject Index (Box 13)
- Series VI. Research Notes, n.d.; 11 vols. (Box 13)
  Slender, spiral-bound notebooks containing field notes on Robertson's research on salmonids in the Upper and Lower No Name Lakes, Wind River Range, Wyoming.
  - Upper No Name Lake, 1941 (Box 13, Volume 1)
  - Lower No Name Lake, 1942 (Box 13, Volume 2)
  - Comparison of Upper and Lower No Name Lakes, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Volume 3)
  - Upper No Name Lake, 1942 (Box 13, Volume 4)
  - Wyoming: General date, 1941 (Box 13, Volume 5)
  - Lower No Name Lake, 1943 (Box 13, Volume 6)
  - Upper No Name Lake, 1944 (Box 13, Volume 7)
  - Wyoming: General date, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Volume 8)
  - Lower No Name Lake, 1944 (Box 13, Volume 9)
  - Spawning K.S., 1948; Kokanee, 1950; Steelhead, 1951; Salmon K.S., 1951, 1948-1951 (Box 13, Volume 10)
  - Migration studies, 1946-1948 (Box 13, Volume 11)
- Series VII. Daily Reminder Books, 1951-1962; 0.5 linear feet (Box 14)
  Daily reminder books, one for earch year, with sporadic and very brief notes, primarily relating to Robertson's work on salmonids.